<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gaming on Patched Atlas</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/gaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gaming on Patched Atlas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Moonstone - Prelude to Dark Souls</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/2021-07-05-moonstone-prelude-to-dark-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/2021-07-05-moonstone-prelude-to-dark-souls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another underrated classic I enjoy is Moonstone, A Hard Day&amp;rsquo;s Knight. Not just because of the punny title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dark Souls games are ones I seem to revisit once every eighteen months or so. There&amp;rsquo;s just something about a brutal fantasy landscape that repeatedly appeals to me. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t tell you exactly what it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I like Moonstone, is because it&amp;rsquo;s surprisingly similar, even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem that way to begin with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moonstone starts out as a classic, turn-based, board game style affair. You take your turn, move your character as far as you want, and decide what to do. You have a number of lives, like most games back then. You&amp;rsquo;re a knight, on a quest. You have a vague storyline. Search for keys by killing monsters across the land, then return to a place of power for a final key before heading to Stone Henge to receive your blessing and win the game. Upgrade your weapons. Armor. Find spells on scrolls. Chug healing potions. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty standard fantasy-game style.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where Moonstone breaks away is the combat. Limited by the original Amiga&amp;rsquo;s one button joystick, it still managed to give you an array of different abilities. Press the button to ready yourself to attack, and then tilt a direction to decide &lt;em&gt;which&lt;/em&gt; attack. It&amp;rsquo;s an elegant system. The battle field allows for 3D movement (as much as was possible back then, at least.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, the gameplay itself is not only wildly gory but utterly and brutally difficult. Even the basic enemies are a threat. And some of the more advanced ones can kill you in a single hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a well-made, enjoyable and very replayable game. But that&amp;rsquo;s not all. Because I play a lot of games, and I don&amp;rsquo;t tend to write about them here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What prompted me to write this blog was another website I found, when looking up information from the game, called &lt;a href=&#34;http://moonstonetavern.co.uk/&#34;&gt;The Moonstone Tavern.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting this website was like stepping back in time. And I mean that in the best possible way. This was the internet I grew up with. There&amp;rsquo;s not an ad in sight. No prompt for cookies. It&amp;rsquo;s not trying to track me at all. Why would it? It follows the traditional internet model of &amp;ldquo;I am a repository of information. Browse me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site, originally built in 2002, is a prime example of the internet I miss. People pursuing their passions, and sharing their findings with whomsoever happens to stumble across them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for something to kill a few days over the summer holiday, you can get the game &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gog.com/game/moonstone_a_hard_days_knight&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for a very reasonable price. And when you do, why not head over to the Moonstone Tavern to learn about the game that will spend the next several days kicking your ass.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
